欢迎加入OCR小组 qq群906722936 字幕优先发布于群内
现在伦敦办事处归我负责了
I'm running this London office now,
我敢保证情况会有所好转的
and I can assure you things will pick up.
前情提要
P R EV I O US LY
我恰好得知纳什先生的
I happen to know that Mr. Nash's
所有员工都背弃了你
entire staff have deserted you.
有时候我会想
Sometimes I do wonder...
这一切值得吗
If it's all worth it?
区域扩张让我们捉襟见肘
This expansion is crippling us.
会有人受伤的
Someone is going to get hurt.
是威灵顿督查
FITZROY: It's Inspector Wellington.
他中枪了
He's been shot.
威廉
: William!
我要喝一杯
: I need a drink.
暖和了吗
IVY: Are you warm enough?
这里有时挺冷的
It can get a bit chilly in here.
暖和 我在这非常舒服 谢谢
WILLIAM: Yes, I'm perfectly comfortable, thank you.
我去把火生上吧
IVY: I'II go set the fire.
艾薇 你能别再大惊小怪的了吗
WILLIAM: Ivy, will you please stop fussing?
我没有
IVY: I'm not fussing!
我去给你做点培根鸡蛋还有炸面包
I'lI go do you some bacon, eggs, and fried bread.
听上去如何
How does that sound?
我得吃多胖啊
Like I'm going to get extremely fat.
我们需要给你补充能量
We need to build up your strength.
是的 艾薇 你过去两周
Yes, Ivy, you have been saying that
都是这么说的
every day for the past two weeks.
我现在很好 谢谢
I'm quite well now, thank you.
好到可以回家了
Well enough to go home.
我找不到包 笔记本还有手套了
I can't seem to find my bag, or my notebook, or my gloves.
你的手套在客厅
Your gloves were in the dining room,
笔记本在厨房水槽里
your notebook by the kitchen sink,
包就在楼梯上
and your bag on the stairs,
我今天绊上差点摔断了脖子
which I nearly broke my neck on this morning.
我从楼下上来的 没看见啊
I've just come downstairs I didn't see it.
因为我把它跟其它你不应该乱放的东西
Because I put them on the table with the rest of your things,
一起放在桌子上了啊
where you should have left them last night.
谢谢
Well, thank you.
患者今早如何了
How is the patient this morning?
他说要回家
He says he's going home.
别理他 艾薇
Just ignore him, Ivy.
我发现这是对付他最好的方法
I find that's the best way to deal with him.
让你好好休息呢 威廉
You were told to rest, William.
而且没有人比艾薇更能照顾好你了
And there's no one better to look after you than Ivy.
是 但我不能整天坐着无所事事啊
Yes, well, I can't just sit here all day.
不用
No.
你可以去厨房吃个早饭
You can come to the kitchen and have breakfast.
一片熏肉就行 艾薇
Just one rasher, please, Ivy.
哈
IVY: Ha!
天
God!
如果早知道你是个如此专横的护士
If I'd known what an appalling nurse you were,
当初我就不会答应来你这恢复身体了
I wouldn't have agreed to convalesce here.
如果我早知道你这个或者事儿这么多
If I'd known what a demanding patient you were,
我也不会让你来了
I wouldn't have let you.
跟你不一样 我可不能像个闲人一样晃来晃去
Well, unlike you, I can't laze around like a lord of leisure.
我的办事处还等着我呢
My office won't run itself.
是啊 我可以想象的到 要管理一个员工得多忙
Yes, I can imagine how busy running a staff of one must be.
我跟你说吧 威廉 我的办事处很快
I can assure you, William, that it will not be long
就会招满员工的
before my office is once again teeming with employees.
纳什父子业务很快就会蒸蒸日上
Things are looking up at Nash and Sons.
虽然他没有儿子
Not that he has any sons.
答应我你会好好休息 听艾薇的话
Promise me you'll rest, and do as Ivy says.
我有选择吗
Do I have a choice?
没有
No.
天 好疼
Oh, God, that hurts!
早上好 克拉伦斯
Good morning, Clarence.
你也早上好啊 斯嘉丽小姐
And a very good morning to you, too, Miss Scarlet.
你这么高兴呢
You're rather chipper.
看来感觉不错啊
You feeling quite well?
从没这么好过
Oh, never better.
我今早一到就发现了
I arrived this morning to be greeted
一个非常令人开心的惊喜
by a most pleasant surprise.
你好啊 伊莱沙
Bonjour, Eliza.
你这是干了什么啊
: What the hell have you done? !
我将生意留给你的时候还欣欣向荣的
I leave you a business that is thriving
回来后却发现马上就要关张了
and come back to find it barely surviving!
你手下的那些男人不肯为女人工作又不是我的错
It's not my fault your men refused to work for a woman!
可我听说是你的态度太差
Well, from what I hear, your manner towards them
让人无法接受
left much to be desired.
我只是想严格管理
I was trying to run a tight ship.
那恭喜你了 伊莱沙 因为你已经没人好管理了
Well, congratulations, Eliza, because you've sunk it.
凡事起步总是会有困难嘛
There were always going to be some teething problems.
你没有员工
You have no staff.
没有客户
No clients.
这可不是什么起步的困难了
I would suggest that's a little more than"teething problems. "
事情已经开始有所好转了
Things are starting to move in the right direction.
我有好几个潜在客户了
I have several potential clients.
你真没必要来的
There's really no need for you to be here.
门上挂的是我的名字
It is my name above the door
你损害的也是我的名誉
and my reputation that is being damaged!
所以我会留在伦敦
So I'm staying in London
直到这里的业务出现好转
until this ship is back on course!
我猜这事是你干的吧
: I assume this is your doing.
我没让纳什先生回来
I did not ask Mr. Nash to return.
我只是在他提出要求时
I merely provided him with progress reports
向他提供了进度报告
whenever he requested them.
而你就都想过要告诉我一声吗
And you didn't think to tell me you were doing that.
他是我老板啊 斯嘉丽小姐
He is my superior, Miss Scarlet.
而且我跟他说了 情况正在有所好转
: And I did tell him that things were picking up.
我钦佩你的乐观 克拉伦斯
Mm, I admire your optimism, Clarence.
但恐怕我和你
But I fear we have
对于“好转”的定义不太相同
different definitions of what constitutes"picking up. "
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我要去伦敦警察局
I'm going to the Fat Goose,
舰队街一半的记者
patronized by the Metropolitan Police,
和皇家法院的律师
half the journalists of Fleet Street,
都会光顾的肥鹅餐厅
and the lawyers of the Royal Courts of Justice.
当我给我的同伴们
When I've oiled my fellow punters
灌了大量的威士忌后
with copious amounts of whiskey,
毫无疑问我会接到一些新案子
I shall, no doubt, be in possession of some new cases.
我希望你能花点时间
If you'd done me the courtesy of actually listening
听我说句话
to what I had to say,
我一小时后就要跟一个客户见面
you'd know that I have a meeting with a client this very hour.
一个有钱也有权势的客户
A client with money and influence.
是否如此得我来判断
I'll be the judge of that.
走吧
Come along.
你的家可真不错 卡特先生
NASH: You have a beautiful home, Mr. Carter.
多亏了我的梅齐
CARTER: AII down to my Maisie.
我只管花钱买下
I'm just the one who paid for it.
我们一年多前搬进来的
We moved in just over a year ago.
费了不少力气
It was hard work,
但最后终于装成我们喜欢的样子了
but we've finally got things how we like them.
之前你们住在哪
And where were you living before?
利兹
Uh, Leeds.
搬到伦敦是为了建个新工厂
Moved down to London to set up a new factory.
纺织行业
I'm in the textile business.
听到这种成功的故事真是太好了
It's good, indeed, to hear such a success story.
在这里
Around here,
你有多少钱似乎并不重要
it doesn't seem to matter what money you've got.
重要的是血统
It's all about your breeding.
贵族们不喜欢新晋的有钱人
The aristocracy do not like new money.
我才不在乎那些人怎么想我
I don't care what the toffs are like with me,
只要他们老婆能善待我的梅齐就行
just as long as their wives treat my Maisie right.
她们对我的确不错
And they do.
一直非常的 随和
: They've been very...accommodating.
我老婆的意思是说
Now, that is her way of saying
她们就是一群势利小人
they're a bunch of stuck- up snobs.
杰克
Jack!
你们要喝点茶吗 先生
Will you be wanting tea, sir?
也许等会吧
Perhaps later.
谢谢你 斯塔福德
CARTER: Thank you, Stafford.
我们能帮到您什么呢 卡特先生
What is it we can help you with, Mr. Carter?
周二晚上 我们为梅齐所在的协会
CARTER: Tuesday evening, we hosted a charity fundraiser
组织了一个慈善筹款活动
for the committee Maisie belongs to.
梅菲尔慈善协会的各位女士
The ladies of the Mayfair Benevolent Society.
活动举办的非常成功
And it was a roaring success, too.
差不多来了100人
Almost 100 souls turned up.
两小时后我们就被打劫了
Two hours in, we were robbed.
里面是什么
ELIZA: What was in it?
纳尔逊的钻石羽毛
CARTER: Nelson's diamond feather,
尼罗河战役后
given to the admiral
土耳其苏丹送给海军上将的
by the sultan of Turkey after the Battle of the Nile.
你是怎么得到的
How did it come into your possession?
在拍卖会上买的
Bought it at auction.
也花了我不少钱
Spent a fortune, too.
纳尔逊一直是我崇拜的英雄
Nelson's always been a hero of mine.
出生没多金贵
Didn't come from money.
但却创下了丰功伟绩
Look what he made of himself.
我们的管家 斯塔福德
Our butler, Stafford,
在10点半的时候发现它丢了
noticed it was missing at half past ten.
我当时特别震惊 在排队上
I was so shocked, I burst into tears
就忍不住掉了眼泪
in front of the whole party.
-让自己看上去像个傻瓜  -没有
I made such a fool of myself. CARTER: No.
一点都不会
You didn't.
再说了 谁在乎他们怎么想
Besides, who cares what they think?
我们需要当晚的宾客名单
NASH: As well as a guest list,
还有在这里服务的
we'll need the names of your staff
员工名单
who were working that night.
我跟员工们都交谈过了
I've spoken to my household.
不是他们
Weren't any of them.
是其中一个客人
It was one of the guests.
我知道肯定是
Ijust know it.
毫无疑问 试图给我个教训
Trying to teach me a lesson, no doubt.
我竟敢比他们强
Daring to better myself.
你报警了吗
And have you informed the police?
让伦敦上流社会受到质疑吗
What, and have all London society questioned?
那他们岂不是会更讨厌我们
They'd resent us even more than they do already.
只有100名客人
There were 100 guests.
其中一个是贼
Only one of em was a thief.
我希望你能秘密的查明
I want you to find who stole from me- -
到底是谁偷的东西
discreetly.
如果你能查得到 我会给你一大笔钱
And when you do, I'll pay you handsomely.
佣金的二倍
Double your fee.
你有什么想说的吗
Is there anything you wish to say?
的确是个值钱的案子
Well, that was promising
接受你的道歉了
Apology accepted.
这不是道歉
It was not an apology.
走了 驾
DRIVER: Go, giddy up!
你道歉了
CLARENCE: You apologized?
虽然话不多吧
ELIZA: Well, not in so many words.
我没道歉
Not in any words.
我只说这的确是个不错的开始
I merely said it was a promising start.
平常费用的二倍
Double the normal fee.
这不只是“不错”而已吧
Id say that's more than promising.
事实说不定是他们监守自盗
It may yet turn out they arranged the theft themselves
只是为了索赔保险金
to claim an insurance payout.
如果是骗保
If it was insurance fraud,
那他们肯定会报警
they'd have to report the theft to the police.
再说了 他们很明显不缺钱
Besides, they don't seem to be short of money,
所以我认为要求一句“干的很棒 伊莱沙”也不算过分吧
so I think a simple"well done, Elizamight be in order.
我可以等到办公室满员之后再说
I'll save that until the office is full again.
是你的手下决定离开的
Your men decided to leave.
不是我逼他们走的
I did not make them.
他们信里可不是这么说的
Well, that's not what they said in their correspondence.
他们还给你写信了
They've been writing to you?
我本来希望情况会自行好转
Well, I had hoped the situation would rectify itself,
这就是为什么我没有早点回来
which is why I didn't come back sooner.
但到最后 我别无选择
But in the end, I had no choice.
我们还是把精力集中到案子上吧
Shall we concentrate on the case?
我应该去询问一下卡特先生家里的员工
I shall make some inquiries into the Carters' household staff.
我不管卡特先生怎么说
And I don't care what Mr. Carter says.
比起一个怀恨在心的富人
It's more likely to be a maid with sticky fingers
我觉得更有可能是一个手脚不干净的女仆干的
than some lord with a grudge. Mm.
我会过一遍参加派对的宾客名单
I'll go through the guest list for the party.
我家里有一本珀西瓦尔的《上院大贵族》
I have a copy of Perceval's"Peerage and Nobility" at home.
上流社会的所有人都会被列入名单
Anyone who's anyone in high society will be listed in it.
也许可以告诉我们要对付的是什么人
It may give us an idea of who we're dealing with.
我会为卡特家的调查起草一份合同
And I shall draw up a contract for the Carter investigation.
我发过去之前你想看看吗
Do you wish to see it before I send it over?
-是的  -是的
Yes. Yes.
写完给我吧
Bring it to me when you're done.
我不是来找你麻烦的
I'm not here to make your life difficult.
我是来帮你的
I'm here to help.
你打算待多久
How long do you intend to stay?
需要多久就多久
As long as it takes.
我没听见你回来
I didn't hear you come in.
那是因为你在睡觉
That's because you were asleep.
还在打呼
And snoring.
我不打呼的
I don't snore.
艾薇马上就回来了 但如果你饿了的话
Ivy will be back soon, but I can make you something
我可以给你弄点吃的
to eat if you'd like. Ah
能别再取笑我的厨艺了吗
Can we please forgo the teasing about my cooking?
不是取笑 有次吃你做的鸡蛋差点吃死我
It's not teasing- - you nearly killed me with some eggs once.
行吧
Well
面包和果酱总不能出什么错吧
You can't go wrong with bread and jam.
而且也不是我做的
And no, I did not make either.
谢了
Thank you.
今天过的如何
: So, how was your day?
大部分时间都很糟糕
For the most part, horrible.
你肯定想不到谁回伦敦来了
You'll never believe who's back in London.
帕特里克·纳什吗
Patrick Nash?
-你怎么知道的  -菲茨罗伊
How do you know that? Fitzroy.
他在每天的日常探望中告诉我的
He told me during his daily visit.
我觉得他每天都来看你真是挺好的
I think that it's nice he comes to see you each day.
等你回去上班后可就没有这种关注度了
You'll miss the attention when you're back at work.
我不着急回去
I'm in no rush to go back
我认真的
I'm serious.
整个地方已经分崩离析了
The whole place is falling apart.
说实话我甚至考虑过就彻底不回去了
To be honest, I've considered not going back at all.
那份工作对你来说就是一切啊
That job is everything to you.
也不是一切吧
Not everything.
这事让我意识到
You know, this has made me realize
在生活中还有其他事需要考虑
that there are other things in life to consider.
比如呢
Such as?
未来
The future.
你的未来就在苏格兰场
Your future's at Scotland Yard.
我觉得这没什么好怀疑的吧
I don't think that's ever been in question.
我说的不是工作
I'm not talking about work.
还记得吗 我们第一次见面就在这个厨房
You know, the first time we met was in this kitchen.
是啊
It was.
我还记得看着你吃东西来着 吃的什么来着
I remember watching you eat- - what was it?
猪肉馅饼吗
Pork pie?
烟熏火腿
Smoked ham.
我还记得你脸上惊恐的表情
I can still remember the look of horror on your face.
那不是惊恐 是着迷
It wasn't horror, it was fascination.
我从没见过有人那么吃东西
I'd never seen anyone eat like that.
到现在还没看到第二个
I still haven't.
那个女人
That woman!
她真是在挑战我的耐心啊
She'd try the patience of a saint!
-你母亲吗  -还有谁
Your mother? Who else?
别问我她痛风怎么样了
Don't ask me about her gout.
我没打算问
I don't intend to.
但我想威廉一定想听听
But I'm sure William would like to hear all about it,
我正好还有工作要做
while I have work to do.
从她的右脚到左脚
Well, it's gone from her right foot to her left foot.
大拇指整个又红又痒 真可怜
Red, itchy skin all over her big toe- - poor thing.
早
Morning.
我有好消息
I come with good news.
我看过了参加卡特家派对的
I went through the list of guests
宾客名单
who attended the Carters' party,
其中许多人都在珀西瓦尔的贵族名单中
many of whom were in the peerage listings in Perceval's,
而且我还发现了其中一名客人
and I believe I've found something of interest
非常有意思
about one of the guests.
你对杰克·卡特的背调都做了哪些
What kind of background checks did you do on Jack Carter?
就是通常那些 姓名 地址 职业
Oh, the usual: name, address, occupation.
你都没想过要查查他的钱是从哪来的吗
You didn't think to look into where his money came from?
纺织业啊 他自己说的
Textiles, as he said.
他名下有几家工厂
He owns a number of factories.
是用他之前
Which he bought with the profits
生意赚的钱买下的
from his original business.
你能直接告诉我发生什么了吗
Will you please just tell me what's happened?
我去见了卡特的佣人们
I went to see Carter's servants.
一听我提可能有人从他那偷东西
AlI were terrified by the mere suggestion
都吓坏了 但没人告诉我原因
they would have stolen from him, but none would say why.
于是我深挖了一下
So, I did some digging.
看上去卡特先生来自于北英格兰
It seems Mr. Carter is from the most notorious
最恶名昭著的犯罪家族
crime family in the North of England.
谋杀 勒索 军火走私
Murder, extortion, gun running.
如果你能做尽职调查
AlI of which you would have known,
就会发现这些
had you done your due diligence,
可你做不到
which, of course, you couldn't
因为整个办事处的人都走光了
because you've lost my entire staff!
他们会对这个暴徒卡特进行调查
They'd have researched this Carter thug properly
并告诉你离他远点
and told you to keep well clear.
昨晚我给卡特先生发了电报
Last night, I sent a telegram to Mr. Carter
说因为之前承诺的事没完成
saying we were unable to take his case
所以目前没法接他的案子了
due to prior commitments.
-纳什先生  -等会儿
Mr. Nash...Just a moment!
今天上午我们俩要坐下来
This morning you and I will sit down
好好制定个新的行动计划
and make a new plan of action,
然后等我们做完
and then once we're through with that...
纳什先生
Mr. Nash.
抱歉打扰了
Apologies for the interruption.
希望你们不太忙
I do hope you are not busy.
我收到你的电报了
I received your telegram.
让我十分不解 所以我想最好还是亲自过来
It caused me some confusion, so I thought it best to come
当面跟你谈谈
and talk to you in person.
卡特先生 如果我
Mr. Carter, if I
没必要解释
CARTER: No need to explain.
我能猜出来发生了什么
I can guess what's happened.
你让我先说完
Just allow me to say my piece.
我老婆和我是盗窃案的受害人
My wife and I were the victims of theft.
要搁以前 这种事我就自己来处理了
There was a time when I would have dealt with this myself.
但我答应过她 我们会像绅士一样
But I've promised her that we will deal with this in a manner
以冷静和文明的方式
that is calm and civilized,
处理此事
as any gentleman might do.
我相信还有许多其他调查机构
I'm sure there are many other investigation agencies
乐意受理你的案件
that would gladly take your case.
我们家那的规矩就是 你一旦答应了
Where I come from, once you give your word,
就不能反悔
you don't go back on it.
所以 为了避免疑义
So, for the avoidance of doubt,
你们会接下这个案子 找到我的珠宝
you will take this case and you will find my jewel.
如果我们做不到呢
If we cannot?
那我就只能让你个人负责了
Then I will hold you personally responsible.
哦还有 这案子我一分钱都不给
Oh, and you'll do it for free.
作为你侮辱我人格的补偿
As compensation for the insult to my character.
一个字都别说
Not...a...word.
我们需要找到那个贼
We need to find that thief.
等你找到后卡特先生会怎么做呢
And what will Mr. Carter do once you find him?
我还真没想 克拉伦斯
That had not yet occurred to me, Clarence,
我谢谢你让原本就很危急的情况
but thank you for making a dire situation
变得更糟心了
even more unsatisfactory.
事已至此
We are where we are.
我们就尽力破案呗
So let's just do our best and try and solve the case.
对吧
Agreed?
你之前提到发现了有意思的事
You mentioned you'd found something of interest.
对
Indeed I did.
钻石羽毛是去年纳尔逊家族
The diamond feather was put up for auction last year
自己进行的拍卖
by Admiral Nelson's family.
据我所知 由于处境艰难
From what I gather, they did so somewhat reluctantly,
他们这样做也是情非得已
due to falling on hard times.
他们被迫卖掉了家族
They've been forced to sell many of the family's
-许多珍贵的财产  -没错
prized possessions. Precisely.
当我浏览卡特加派对的客人名单时
As I was going through the list of guests
发现了一位法伦勋爵
who attended the Carters' party, I came across a Lord Fallon.
他和他老婆是慈善机构的赞助人
He and his wife are patrons of a charity
专门帮助从海军退役的军人
that help retired sailors from the Royal Navy.
原来
Turns out
法伦勋爵母亲那边
Lord Fallon has a link on his mother's side
与海军上将霍雷肖·纳尔逊有亲戚关系
to Admiral Horatio Nelson.
法伦是纳尔逊的表亲
Fallon is Nelson's cousin?
这样他就有动机和机会
Which gives him motive and opportunity
拿回珍贵的传家宝
to claim back a treasured family heirloom.
我们应该去拜访他一下了
We should pay him a visit.
是
We should.
但我们需要一个说得过去的理由
But we'll need a cover story.
我妻子和我一直都是艺术赞助人
NASH: My wife and I have always been patrons of the arts.
她出主意说我们应该过来和你们喝个茶
It was her idea that we come to take tea with you,
法伦勋爵和夫人
Lord and Lady Fallon,
也许可以多了解更一下你们的慈善事业
and that we might learn more of your own charitable works.
有新的赞助人我们总是很乐意欢迎的
It is always a pleasure to welcome new benefactors.
谢谢你肯考虑我们
Thank you for considering us.
她是个非常无私的人
She is such a selfless person.
总是想着其他人
She's always thinking of others.
别听我亲爱的丈夫乱说
Do not listen to my dear husband.
是他从不顾自己只想着他人
It is he who thinks of all but himself.
从来没有比他更善良 更高尚的人了
Never was there a, a kinder, more honorable man.
你们新到伦敦的吗
You are newly arrived in London?
我们之前好像没见过面
I do not believe our paths have crossed before.
我们一直住在西印度群岛 那边有些生意要照顾
We have, until recently, been in the West Indies,
最近才来伦敦的
where we have some business interests.
但我相信我们有共同的熟人
But we have, I believe, some mutual acquaintances.
卡特先生和夫人
A Mr. and Mrs. Carter.
他们是你们的朋友吗
They are friends of yours?
生意往来而已
Business acquaintances.
我听说卡特夫妇的慈善舞会取得了巨大的成功
I hear the Carters' charity ball was a roaring success,
尽管结局有些让人难过
although ended in somewhat sad circumstances.
偷窃的事
Mm. The theft.
的确是太遗憾了
LADY FALLON: It was a shame indeed.
可怜的卡特夫人费了那么大力气组织的活动
Poor Mrs. Carter had put much work into the event,
结果却以这种方式告终
and for it to end in such a way
她可是出尽了丑
She made a damn fool of herself.
-亲爱的  -怎么了
Dearest. What?
本来就是嘛
She did.
她的丈夫也好不到哪去
That husband of hers is no better.
一对粗人
Uncouth, the pair of them.
也许这时候在这说这话不太合适
Perhaps this is not the time nor the place...
别以为在我自己的家里
Do not presume to tell me
还轮到你告诉我
what I can and cannot say
我能说什么不能说什么 夫人
in my own home, madam.
不如我们回到
Perhaps we might return
你们提的捐款的话题
to this donation you mentioned.
你们的慈善机构
Uh, your charity is, I believe
是支持皇家海军
in support of the elderly and infirm sailors
年老体弱的水手的 对吧
of the Royal Navy.
没错
That is correct.
考虑到你们家族和国内最伟大的英雄
Which is apt, given your connection
霍雷肖·纳尔逊上将之间的关系
to the greatest hero this country's ever seen:
还真是挺合适的
Admiral Horatio Nelson.
天
Goodness.
要是那样的话
Well, in that case,
对上将的钻石羽毛的盗窃
the theft of the admiral's diamond feather
恐怕你们是最难过的吧
must have dismayed you more than most,
毕竟那是你们的传家宝
given it's practically a family heirloom.
我都不太记得自己的远方表亲了
I'd hardly call a distant cousin family.
至于盗窃 我知道是谁干的
And as for the theft, I know exactly who stole it.
-谁  -谁
Who? Who?
我们夫妻俩也挺八卦的哈
We do love a little gossip now and then.
维奇曼男爵夫人
Baroness Weichmann.
令人生厌的女人 总是四处去搜刮救济品
Dreadful woman- - always scratching around for handouts.
我听说她试图支付
I heard she was trying to
回普鲁士的旅费
pay for her passage back to Prussia.
负债累累那家伙
Riddled with debts, that one.
这个普鲁士男爵夫人值得去见见
This Prussian baroness is worth a visit.
法伦很明显恨那个女人
Fallon clearly loathes the woman.
他给我的印象是谁都不喜欢
He strikes me as someone who likes very few,
包括自己的老婆
including his own wife.
你看到她脖子上的於伤了吗
Did you see the bruises on her neck?
是他干的 毫无疑问
It was him, no doubt.
你们为什么用这种眼神看着我
Why are you looking at me like that?
我们不想打扰你 长官
We didn't want to disturb you, sir.
你看上去好安详
IVY: You looked so peaceful.
就像个小男孩
Like a little boy.
我不需要你的帮助 谢谢
I don't need your help, thank you.
是 长官 抱歉 长官
Yes, sir, sorry, sir.
他每次一醒过来就会这样
He's always like this when he first wakes up.
我去给你拿点茶和蛋糕
I'll go and fetch some tea and cake.
不要蛋糕 艾薇
No cake, Ivy.
胡说
Nonsense.
如果我不尽早离开这 我就得胖成猪了
If I don't get out of here soon, I'm going to run to fat.
不管艾薇给你吃什么 都是为你好
Well, whatever Ivy's feeding you, it's doing you good.
你每天看上去都比前一天更好了
Each day, you look a little better.
嗯
Yes.
说到这个 奥利弗 你不用每天都来看我
On that, Oliver, you don't have to visit me every day.
但我挺愿意来的 长官
But I look forward to it, sir.
除非你不想我来
Unless you'd prefer I didn't?
当然不是
: Of course not.
那么
: So...
大日子啊
: Important day.
是啊 长官
Yes, sir.
美国大使馆在等着我
The American Embassy awaits.
我特别想得到这次借调的机会
I want this secondment more than anything.
是个不错的机会
It's quite the opportunity.
纽约哎
New York!
想想看
Imagine that.
你和你父亲之间隔着大洋
And an ocean between you and your father
毫无疑问会距离产生美吧
has its benefits, no doubt.
我可没这么想过
Never occurred to me.
我得给大使的工作人员做个演讲
I have to make a speech to the ambassador's staff.
我想跟你分享
I hoped to share it with you.
我的建议是 别让他们听烦了
: My advice is, don't bore them.
尽量简短 直达重点
Make it short and to the point.
我想的跟你一样 长官
My thoughts exactly, sir.
听说你想卖掉豪宅时
NASH: We could not believe it when we heard you were looking
我们简直不敢相信 男爵夫人
to sell your splendid estate, Baroness,
因为我和我妻子正想在这个地区买房呢
since my wife and I are eager to buy in this area.
是 你们怎么听说的
WEICHMANN: Yes, how did you hear of it?
法伦男爵提了一嘴
ELIZA: Oh, Lord Fallon mentioned it in passing.
我是一个热衷于骑马的女人
I'm a keen horsewoman, and, uh, it's so very rare
在伦敦市中心能找到这么好的房子可不多见
to find such a grand house in the middle of London...
尤其是还有马厩
Mm- hmm. ...with stables to boot.
其实让这里荒废如斯
Well, it was not my intention
不是我的本意
to let things fall into such disrepair.
我想维护起来也很贵吧
Expensive to upkeep, too, I'd imagine.
你们想出个什么价格呢
How much exactly were you looking to offer?
财务是我丈夫管的 男爵夫人
Oh, finance is my husband's department, Baroness.
我几乎不懂财务 觉得它很无聊
I rarely understand it and find it quite tiresome,
几天前我也对我的好友
and said very much the same to my great friend
梅齐·卡特太太说了同样的话
Mrs. Maisie Carter just the other day.
你认识卡特一家吗
Oh, you know the Carters?
我虽然说是朋友
I say"friend. "
但考虑到我们社会地位之间的差异
Given the chasm between our social standing,
可能说她是个熟人更合适
she is perhaps more of an acquaintance.
但我很同情她
But my heart does go out to her.
你听说他们的钻石羽毛被盗了吗
Did you hear about the theft of their diamond feather?
夫人
Madam?
您有客来访
You have a visitor.
真的很抱歉
I do apologize,
但我得照顾一下客人
but I must see to my guest.
我们另约时间再谈吧
Let us carry this negotiation on some other time.
我的女仆会告诉你我什么时候有空
My maid will let you know when I'm next available.
日安
Good day.
男爵夫人
Baroness.
帕特里克
Patrick
你认识他吗
Do you know him?
吉布森先生
Mr. Gibson.
他是个掮客
He's a dealer.
哪一行的
In what?
失窃的艺术品和珠宝
Stolen art and jewelry.
克拉伦斯
Clarence.
我需要一个二流艺术品掮客的信息
I need information on a second- rate art dealer.
名字叫吉布森先生
A Mr. Gibson.
我想您应该先看看这个
I think you ought to see this first.
谁寄的
Who sent this?
我不知道
I don't know.
没有名字 也没有签名
There's no name or signature.
一定是我出去买午餐的时候送来的
It must have been posted when I went out to buy my luncheon.
你要找的钻石羽毛就在
"The diamond feather you seek can be found
法伦勋爵的写字台上
in Lord Fallon's writing desk. "
我当时正在演讲
I was in the middle of my speech,
本来渐入佳境呢 他们就叫我停下来
just getting into my stride, and they told me to stop.
去拿威士忌 艾薇
Whiskey, Ivy.
我试着阐述自己的观点
I tried to put my case forward,
但他们都没听就让我走了
but they dismissed me out of hand.
本来是一个千载难逢的机会
It was a golden opportunity.
在纽约 我可以活出自己的样子
In New York, I could have been anyone I wanted to be.
那里没人认识我 也没人知道我父亲是谁
No one there knows me or who my father is.
这本来是一个新的开始
It could have been a fresh start.
他们的理由是什么
Did they give a reason?
当然是缺乏经验
Lack of experience, apparently.
听起来他们好像想找某个
It sounds like they're hoping for someone
像你这样服务多年的人 长官
with more years of service, such as yourself, sir.
你是想甩掉我吗 警探
Are you trying to get rid of me, Detective?
当然不是 长官
Oh, of course not, sir.
你可以明年再申请
You can always apply again next year.
有点耐心吧
Just, just be patient.
你说得对 长官
You're right, sir.
你总是正确的
You're always right.
我最好还是回了
I'd best get back.
文件越摞越高
The files keep rolling in
我不想让菲尔普斯指责我摸鱼
and I don't want Phelps to accuse me of shirking.
谢谢 伍兹小姐
Thank you, Miss Woods.
不客气 警探
Pleasure, Detective.
奥利弗
Oliver?
你是个好警察
You're a good copper.
别忘了这点
Don't forget that.
谢谢你 长官
Thank you, sir.
那孩子很敬重你
That boy thinks the world of you.
你会是一个好父亲
You'll make a good father.
你想过拥有自己的家庭吗
Would you like family of your own one day?
我能直说吗
Can I speak my mind?
让我再喝一杯威士忌吧
Will I need another whiskey?
考虑到你刚刚经历的事
Given what you've just been through,
相信你不需要我来提醒
I'm sure you don't need me to tell you this,
人生苦短 不要浪费光阴
but life is short- - don't waste it.
我不知道你和阿拉贝拉
I don't know what happened
之间发生了什么
between you and Arabella,
但我猜的到 你们结束的原因是什么
but I can take a good guess at the reason why it ended.
你不觉得现在是时候告诉她了吗
So don't you think it's about time you told her?
告诉谁
Told who?
我贿赂了一个下班的女仆
I bribed one of the maids as she was leaving.
管家今晚休息
Housekeeper has the night off
法伦一家也该去剧院了
and the Fallons are due to go to the theater.
他们一走 房子就空了
So, once they've left, the house will be empty.
事情不会这么简单的
It can't be this easy, can it?
一张从天而降的纸条
A note just miraculously tells us
告诉我们去哪找钻石羽毛
where the diamond feather is hidden.
没错 但至少得调查一下
Well, we have to at least investigate.
另外 法伦大人给我的印象是树敌颇多
Besides, Lord Fallon strikes me as a man with plenty of enemies.
说到纸条
Speaking of notes,
你的人在信里怎么说我的
what did your men say about me in their letters?
最好还是别管了
I think it's best just to leave that be.
我声明 那不是你的错
And, for the record, it was not your fault.
-谢谢你 帕特里克  -是我的错
Thank you, Patrick. It was mine.
我就不该让你负责
I should never have left you in charge.
什么
What? !
驾
Hup.
你说不该让我负责是什么意思
What do you mean you should never have left me in charge?
非要现在说吗
This is not the time.
赶紧去找他的书桌
Let's find his desk.
看看纸条上写的对不对
See if the note was right.
你的手下辞职是因为他们不想为女人工作
Your men resigned because they didn't want to work for a woman.
我可没有解雇任何人
I didn't dismiss a single one of them.
除了马修斯吧
Apart from Matthews?
他吃个午饭花了三个小时
He was taking three hours for lunch.
-还有辛普森  -我不喜欢他的态度
And Simpson? I didn't care for his manner.
除了这两个 其他人可赖不着我
But aside from those two, I bear no responsibility.
-还有彼得斯吗  -好吧
And Peters? Fine.
我确实解雇了几个人 但我不后悔
I did dismiss some of them, and I don't regret it.
很好 反正他们说无论如何都要离开
Good, cause they told me they would have left anyway.
-什么  -我只是如实传话
What? Well, don't shoot the messenger.
有人来了
Someone's coming.
这边
This way.
我应该看一眼吗 看看是谁
Shall I have a look? See who it is?
想看就看呗 反正你总是任性而为
: Do what you want- - you always do anyway.
没时间闹别扭了
This is no time to sulk!
我没闹别扭
I'm not sulking!
就算钻石羽毛真在法伦的桌子上
If the diamond feather was in Fallon's desk,
现在也被别人拿走了
someone else has it now.
你昨晚什么时候回家的
What time did you come home last night?
你怎么跟我父亲似的
I wasn't aware you were my father.
我只是想和你谈谈 仅此而已
I had, uh, Id hoped to speak to you, that's all.
谈什么 如果你是想回家
About what? If this is about you going home,
你的身体还没恢复呢
you're not well enough yet.
不 不是谈那个
No, it's not that.
-我知道是什么了  -你才不知道
Oh, I know what it is. No, you don't.
希望你能先听我说
But if you would just listen for a moment
是关于菲茨罗伊警探的 对吧
It's Detective Fitzroy, isn't it?
他已经告诉你我的客户是谁了 我自己的安全不需要
He's told you who my client is- - I do not need you lecturing me
-你来指手画脚 威廉  -伊莱沙 求你了
about my safety, William. Eliza, will you please,
哪怕就一次 先听我说好吗
for once, just listen to what I have to say?
什么 你的客户是谁
Why? Who is your client?
你有危险吗
Are you in danger?
现在不方便聊 威廉
Now's not the time, William.
我真的得去工作了
I really must be getting to work.
如果真的是法伦勋爵偷了钻石羽毛
If Lord Fallon did steal the diamond feather,
那偷他的又是谁
then who stole it from him?
我们还得查清楚
And we still need to find out
这封匿名信是谁寄的
who sent the anonymous letter.
同意
Agreed.
奇了怪了 我们相处一上午了
How curious we're halfway through the morning,
居然还没有吵架
and there's yet to be a cross word between us.
帕特里克 时间还早呢
It's still early, Patrick.
我找到一份奢侈品销赃的掮客名单
I have a list of dealers who trade in stolen luxury goods,
但我还没找到吉布森先生的资料
but I'm yet to find anything on a Mr. Gibson.
交给我吧
Leave it with me.
我知道去哪里找他
I have an idea where we might find him.
你是吉布森先生吧
Mr. Gibson, isn't it?
你是哪位
Who wants to know?
我是威灵顿督查的同事
I'm a colleague of Inspector Wellington.
我记得你曾协助他办案
I believe you once assisted him on a case.
我从没听说过他
I've never heard of him.
真的吗
Oh, really?
我一定是弄错了
I must be mistaken.
也许我该把他叫来
Perhaps I should go and fetch him.
呃 我想起来了 我确实记得那个督查
Uh, now, come to think of it, I do remember the inspector.
我就知道你会想起来的
I thought you might.
有什么可以效劳的
So, how can I help you?
你和维奇曼男爵夫人有什么生意往来
What's your business with Baroness Weichmann?
我从来没听说过她
I've never heard of her.
我看见你在她的马厩见过她
I saw you meet her at her stables.
可能是她想请你帮忙
She's requested your help
出手卖掉某件偷来的古董
to sell a stolen artifact, perhaps.
我可以向你保证
I can assure you,
我只经销合法商品
I trade only in legitimate goods,
都是流传有序的交易
sold with full provenance.
这就怪了
Well, that's curious,
因为威灵顿督查很确定你干的
since Inspector Wellington was quite sure that you did
的确是赃物交易
indeed trade in stolen goods.
要不我还是去把他找来
Perhaps I should go and fetch him after all,
好给你提个醒
to clear this muddle up.
男爵夫人没有要出手赃物
Well, the, the baroness has offered no stolen goods.
但我确实付给她一笔小小小的佣金
: But I do pay her a small commission
让她给我介绍想偷偷
to bring me wealthy ladies looking
卖掉自己财产的富婆们
to sell their possessions- - discreetly.
通常是在她们丈夫不知情的情况下
Often without the knowledge of their husbands.
男爵夫人赚到佣金了吗
And has the baroness earned her commission
她有给你介绍客户吗
and provided you with any clients?
我今天中午就要和一个客户见面
I've got a meeting with one of them today at noon.
这位幸运的女士是谁呢
Who might this lucky lady be?
她叫法伦
Her name's Fallon.
艾米丽·法伦夫人
Lady Emily Fallon.
他向我保证 和法伦夫人会面之后
He assured me he'd come to the office immediately
会马上到办公室来
after his meeting with Lady Fallon
告诉我们她想卖掉的是什么
and confirm what it was she wishes to sell.
你信任他吗
Do you trust him?
-暂时利用罢了  -尽管如此
Not remotely. Nevertheless,
这是我们目前最好的线索了
it's the best lead we have.
同意
Agreed.
你能不能别再同意我了
Can you stop agreeing with me?
真让我如坐针毡
It's most disconcerting.
下午好
Good afternoon.
你是斯塔福先生吧
It's Mr. Stafford, isn't it?
有客人上门
We have visitors.
是的 谢谢你 克拉伦斯
Yes, thank you, Clarence.
很高兴又见面了 斯嘉丽小姐 纳什先生
Nice to see you again, Miss Scarlet, Mr. Nash.
很抱歉没有预约就贸然造访
So sorry to turn up without an appointment.
我们正要去街角吃午饭
We were just on our way to luncheon round the corner.
杰克要带我去吉尔伯特餐厅
Jack's taking me to Gilbert's.
路过的时候 我突然想到
And as we were passing, I thought
干嘛不顺便过来听听这个案子的最新进展呢
why not drop in and get an update on the case?
请放心
Please be assured
我们正在全力侦破
it has our full attention,
一旦我们有任何进展
and as soon as we have any developments,
你会第一个知道的
you'll be the first to know.
斯塔福
Stafford,
把卡特夫人送上马车
take Mrs. Carter to the carriage.
很高兴又见到你
So nice to see you again.
再见 卡特夫人
Mrs. Carter.
我的家人都听说了 有人偷了我的东西
Word has got back to my family that someone has stolen from me.
我的兄弟们正等着看我的笑话
My brothers are dining out on how funny that is.
我不喜欢被人嘲笑 纳什先生
And I don't like to be laughed at, Mr. Nash.
是的 我完全理解
Yes, I can see that.
所以 你必须把目前
So, you're gonna tell me everything
掌握的一切都告诉我
you've found out so far.
我们还在跟进几个不同的调查方向
We're still following up on different lines of inquiry.
我要名字 地址 还有
I want names, and addresses, and...
杰克 我们要迟到了
Jack! We're going to be late.
马上来了 亲爱的
Just coming, my darling.
你们还有一天时间
You've got one more day.
我要去市场了
I'm going to the market.
给你买些好吃的猪排当晚餐
I'll pick you up some nice pork chops for your dinner.
艾薇
Ivy...
你有信纸吗
Do you have any writing paper?
最上面的抽屉 右边
Top drawer, right- hand side.
里面也有笔
You'll find a pen in there, too.
表达我的
Convey my
表达
Convey?
老天爷
For God's sake
我们唯一的线索就是这个狡猾的艺术品掮客
Our only lead is this crooked art dealer.
如果他这条线没有结果
And if he's let us down,
明天我们得空手面对卡特了
tomorrow we'll face Carter empty- handed.
如果他和法伦女士的会面是在中午
: If his meeting with Lady Fallon was at noon,
他现在应该已经到了
he should have been here by now.
请不要再走来走去了 都把搞我紧张了
Please stop pacing, you're making me nervous.
很好 凭啥就我一个人焦虑呢
Good- I don't see why I should suffer alone.
我带了午餐来
I've brought some lunch!
现在不吃 克拉伦斯
Not now, Clarence.
斯嘉丽小姐和我在等这个吉布森
Miss Scarlet and I are waiting for this Gibson fellow,
尽管很有可能他不会出现了
even though there's a strong possibility he will not show.
-就算他没出现也不是我的错  -这全都是你的错
If he doesn't, it's not my fault. AlI of this is your fault.
-这位吉布森先生戴眼镜吗  -是的
Does this Mr. Gibson wear spectacles? Yes.
而且有一头浓密的头发
And possess an abundant head of hair?
是的
Yes.
他是不是总带着点痛苦的表情
And does he have a somewhat pained expression,
可能是因为神经质吧
presumably due to a nervous disposition?
-是的  -是的
Yes. Yes.
他就在外面
Hm- - he's outside.
够慢的
You took your time.
你有法伦夫人的消息吗
You have news on Lady Fallon?
她打算和丈夫离婚 正在筹钱
She's seeking to finance a divorce from her husband.
她在布拉汉姆酒店订了房间
She got rooms at the Brabham Hotel.
马尔堡套房
Marlborough Suite.
她想晚点约我在那见面 把要卖的东西给我
Wants to meet there later, give me what she has to sell.
她到底想卖的是什么
What exactly is it that she wants to sell?
纳尔逊上将的钻石羽毛
Admiral Nelson's diamond feather.
有可能是法伦大人从
It's possible that Lord Fallon did steal the jewel
卡特先生那里偷了珠宝 然后呢
from Mr. Carter, but then what?
法伦夫人又从自己的丈夫那里偷来了
Lady Fallon stole it from her own husband?
也许吧
Hm, perhaps.
但我们还是要查清是谁寄的匿名信
But we still need to find out who sent the anonymous note.
按照要求 我去布拉汉姆酒店查过了
As requested, I checked at the Brabham.
马尔堡套房的确是
The Marlborough Suite is indeed
法伦夫人经常去的地方
where Lady Fallon regularly visits.
但房费不是她或她丈夫付的
But the rooms are not paid for by her or her husband.
谁给他们买的单
Well, who does pay for them?
杰克·卡特
Jack Carter.
法伦夫人和卡特
So Lady Fallon and Carter
搞在一起了吗
are having an affair?
你觉得这可能吗
Does that make sense to you?
再没什么比这更让我惊讶了
Very little surprises me anymore.
我要再查查卡特的档案
I'm going to take another look at Carter's file,
看看能不能找到其他和法伦家族有关的线索
see if I can make any other connection to the Fallons.
伊莱沙
Eliza.
威廉 你来这做什么
William, what are you doing here?
你应该呆在家里休息
You should be at home, resting
是的
Yes.
但我想和你谈谈
I wanted to speak to you.
虽然我今天早上刚试过
I did attempt to this morning.
抱歉 你盘问我的时候总让我很紧张
Sorry, you just make me nervous when you start to question me.
但如果是关于我目前的调查
But it was about my current investigation.
不 完全是另外一件事
No, it's about something else entirely.
一件我不吐不快的事
Something that I need to get off my chest.
但作为一个不善吐露心声的男人
But as a man ill at ease with getting things off his chest,
我想最好的办法是
I thought the best thing might be to, um
是什么
To
吉布森刚送来了一条信息
Gibson's just sent a message.
他4点要见法伦女士
He's meeting Lady Fallon at 4: 00.
也就是20分钟后
Well, that's in 20 minutes.
纳什先生正在叫一辆出租马车
Mr. Nash is hailing down a cab.
我不着急 你去吧
This can wait- - you go.
好吧
Well
看来你明显感觉好多了
Given you're clearly feeling a little better,
今晚吃顿饭怎么样
perhaps dinner this evening?
我会在吉尔伯特餐厅预订个位子
I'lI make a reservation at Gilbert's.
我们到时候再谈
We'll talk then.
我会在8点前到家 我保证
I'll be home by 8: 00, I promise.
你爱上她了
You are in love with her.
除非你能说服我没这回事
Unless you can convince me otherwise.
那我祝你好运
Well, I wish you luck.
我这么说是出于友谊 不是恶意
And I say this out of friendship, not malice.
一切都比不上伊莱沙的雄心
Eliza's ambition will outweigh everything,
包括她对你的感情
even her feelings for you.
对她来说 永远都不会满足
Nothing will ever be enough for her.
你想象中的未来也满足不了她
Certainly not the future you envisage.
法伦夫人
Lady Fallon?
我们知道钻石羽毛在你手里
We know you have the diamond feather.
我不知道你们在说什么
I have no idea what you're talking about.
你把它藏这了
You kept it hidden here.
你打算在这里把它卖了
And this is where you plan to sell it.
不 不 不要
No, no, don't!
我和艾米丽 法伦夫人
Myself and Emily Lady Fallon- -
我们是通过梅菲尔妇女协会认识的
we met through the Mayfair ladies' society
我们发现彼此的婚姻都一样的不幸福
and found we were both as unhappily married as each other.
很讽刺吧
Funny, innit?
我丈夫居然想被法伦勋爵那样的人认可
My husband wants to be accepted by the likes of Lord Fallon.
一个喝多了就打老婆的男人
A man who beats his wife when he's had one too many.
你需要钱离婚
You needed money to fund a divorce,
所以你偷了钻石羽毛
so you stole the diamond feather.
其实是我偷的
It was me who stole it.
我想帮助艾米丽 但我也想惩罚杰克
I wanted to help Emily, but I also wanted to punish Jack.
我甚至从来不想搬来伦敦
I never even wanted to move to London.
我很喜欢以前生活的地方
I was happy where we were.
我们都是在那里长大的
Where we both grew up.
我们属于故乡
We belonged.
而我来这座城市以后
And all I've had since I've come
得到的只有排斥和蔑视
to this city is rejection and contempt.
艾米丽是唯一一个对我好的人
And Emily's the only one who's ever shown me any kindness.
聚会结束后 我丈夫喝多了
After the party, my husband had had too much to drink,
梅齐看到我的伤痕时 她难过极了
and when Maisie saw my bruises, she was upset.
她本是想把珠宝给我
She was meant to give me the jewel,
可最后 她把它放在了我丈夫的桌子里
but instead, she put it in my husband's desk
然后给你寄了那张便条
and sent you the note.
我指望你能把事情告诉杰克
I hoped you would tell Jack
然后他会彻底处理掉法伦
and he would deal with Fallon once and for all.
运气好的话
With any luck,
艾米丽就不用忍受离婚的耻辱了
Emily wouldn't have to suffer the humiliation of a divorce
因为她会变成寡妇
and instead she would be a widow.
我的丈夫 他确实罪有应得
My husband is, oh, he is many things.
但我不希望他的死让我良心不安
But I did not want his death on my conscience.
所以你把它从桌子上又偷了回来
So you stole it back from the desk.
如果你把真相告诉杰克
If you tell Jack any of this
天知道他会对我做什么
Well, God knows what he'll do to me.
对我们俩
To both of us.
我们怎么跟卡特说
What do we tell Carter?
我们不能告诉他真相 这是肯定的
We can't tell him the truth, that's for sure.
但如果我们不交出她们 卡特就会让我们背锅
But if we don't hand them over, Carter will come after us.
我知道这很自私
And I know itjs selfish of me,
但我很想多活几年
but I'd very much like to carry on living.
怎么了
What is it?
卡特是个有钱人
Carter's a wealthy man.
在国内他想住哪里都行
He could live anywhere in the country,
但他还是选择了搬来伦敦
and yet he chose to move to London,
加入绅士俱乐部 和爵士们还有夫人们混在一起
to join gentlemen's clubs and mix with lords and ladies.
为什么要那么做呢
Why would he do that?
我们说这个有什么用
Why are we discussing this now, exactly?
答案是 因为他想要混进圈子里
The answer is because he wants to belong.
你是在制定计划吗
Is this you formulating a plan?
如果是的话 希望你计划最后让我活着
If so, I do hope my survival is factored into it.
我从来没怀疑过你的能力
I never doubted you for a minute.
现在告诉我
Now tell me.
是谁拿的
Who took it?
我和斯嘉丽小姐
Neither myself nor Miss Scarlet
都不会告诉你谁拿的
will be giving you that information.
我们已经完璧归赵了 事情就此结束吧
We've returned what is stolen, which is an end to the matter.
我再问一遍
I will ask once more.
我最后一次这么礼貌地问你
And it will be the last time I do so politely.
我们非常了解你的威胁 卡特先生
We're more than aware of the threat you pose, Mr. Carter.
我相信让人消失是你的专长
Making people disappear is a speciality of yours, I believe.
利兹的酒馆老板
A publican in Leeds.
赫尔的码头工人
A dock worker in Hull.
还有其他的 都写在这里了
There are others, too- it's all in here.
这个你留着吧
You can keep this.
我们把同样的文件复印了很多份
We've made numerous copies of the same documents.
目前都存放在一个秘密地点 如果我和纳什先生
They're currently in a secret location and will be released
受到任何伤害 那么文件就会被公之于众
should any harm come to myself or Mr. Nash.
你以为警察不知道这事吗
You think the police don't know this already?
不过是谣言和道听途说罢了
A bunch of rumor and hearsay?
如果有证据 我早就进监狱了
If there were any evidence, I'd be in prison.
我们不会把文件寄给警察
Well, it's not the police we'd send it to.
而是寄给来参加你宴会的客人
It's the guests who attended your party.
你选择搬来伦敦
You chose to move to London
与上层社会的大人物混在一起
to mix amongst the great and the good.
就像你的英雄纳尔逊上将那样的人 你想混进
Like your hero, Admiral Nelson, you wish to rise
社会的最高层圈子
to the very top of society.
但要是他们知道了你的真实身份 那就彻底没戏了
But that will never happen if they know who you really are.
比你更厉害的人
Rumor and hearsay have destroyed
也敌不过风言风语 卡特先生
greater men than you, Mr. Carter.
但是呢
However,
我们也希望你的声誉不受玷污
it's our wish that your reputation remain intact,
那些你想巴结的人也永远不会知道这些
and that none of those you wish to impress learn any of this.
当然 我们还是要向你收费的
We will, of course, be expecting our fee.
更确切的说 按照协议 你要加倍付我们报酬
Or, rather, double our fee, as agreed.
太好了
Splendid.
好吧 我们祝你日安 纳什先生
Well, then, we shall bid you good day- Mr. Nash?
克拉伦斯 真希望你也能亲眼看看
Oh, I wish you'd been there, Clarence.
卡特简直是一败涂地
Carter didn't stand a chance.
为获得双倍报酬干杯
To getting double our feel
真了不起 斯嘉丽小姐 干得好
That is quite something, Miss Scarlet- - well done.
谢谢你 克拉伦斯
Thank you, Clarence.
这可是你第一次夸我
That may be the first compliment you've ever given me.
好吧
Oh, well!
我以后尽量不养成这个坏习惯
I shall endeavor not to make a habit of it.
如果你不介意
If you'll excuse me,
我得去把这比报酬记录到财务报表上
I'll go and add our latest fee to the balance sheet.
很多人给我的信里谈到过你
Of all those who wrote to me about you,
克拉伦斯对你的评价是最高的
Clarence was the most complimentary.
以前他从没对谁如此赞赏过
Well, as complimentary as he can ever be.
只很遗憾我的手下没有
It's just a shame my men didn't...
我们好容易和谐相处了 帕特里克
We're having a moment of harmony, Patrick.
请不要毁了它
Please do not ruin it.
我是想说 我的手下无法
I was going to say, it's just a shame
像我这么了解你 真是太遗憾了
my men didn't see you as I do.
你是个杰出的侦探
As an exceptional detective
还是个了不起的女人
and a remarkable woman.
在你走上正轨之前 我本该待在这里
I should have stayed here until you'd settled in.
所以 这些已经发生的事 我也要
So, I must take some responsibility
承担一定责任
for what happened.
也许有些时候
Perhaps there were times where
我对你的手下有点专横
I was a little high- handed with your men.
我们重新开始怎么样
What say we start again?
我们再招新员工
We'll hire new staff.
我用巴黎分公司的钱作为启动资金
I'll fund it with the money from the Paris branch
一直到事业上了正轨
and stay until things are running smoothly.
我们会让纳什父子侦探公司再次变得伟大
And we'll make Nash and Sons great once more.
用你的大脑
With your brains
还有我的美貌 妥妥的十拿九稳
and my good looks, I mean, how can we fail?
不
Oh, no.
对不起 帕特里克 我得走了
Sorry, Patrick, I must go.
谢谢你
Thank you.
威廉
William?
你要去哪里
Where are you going?
你还没好彻底 不能回家
You're not well enough to go home yet!
我不打算回家
I'm not going home.
我去见上级了 而上级也同意了
I've been to see the super and he's agreed.
我要去纽约了
I'm going to New York.
我要被借调了
I'm taking the secondment.
走一年吗
For a year?
是的 一年
For a year.
就因为我吃饭迟到了吗
This is because I was late for dinner?
不是
No.
是因为我爱你
This is because I love you.
我居然让你无话可说
It's a rare occurrence
这种情况可不多见
that I cause you to be speechless.
早知我应该多向你表白几次
Perhaps I should tell you that I love you more often.
好吧 既然你爱我 你却要离开
Well, you, you love me, and yet you're leaving?
有些事情必须改变了 伊莱沙
Something has to change, Eliza.
不是你改变
Perhaps for you,
就是我改变
perhaps for me.
这样我们就有时间考虑自己的选择了
This will, uh, give us the time to consider our options.
-我不明白  -不 你明白的
I, I don't understand. Yes, you do.
如果我们要在一起
If we are to be together,
那我就不能留在苏格兰场了
then I cannot remain at Scotland Yard
因为你是一个私家侦探
with you a private detective.
我也不能再陪在你身边
Nor can I be around you anymore without,
却没能和你在一起
without being with you.
你让我进退维谷
You have put me in an impossible situation.
所以 这是我的错咯
So, this is my fault?
是的
Yes.
这不是告别
This isn't goodbye.
只是暂时分开
It's goodbye for now.
自从威灵顿督查走了以后
You've not spoken of Inspector Wellington
你没有提起过他
since he's been gone.
你明显很难过 对他很生气
You're clearly upset and angry with him.
我不难过 也不生气
I'm not upset, nor am I angry.
如果你要管理这家机构
If you are to run this agency,
你首先必须是一个女商人
you must first and foremost be a businesswoman.
我不回巴黎了
I'll not be returning to Paris
直到你让我相信你能做到
until you convince me you understand this.